NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
〜
BASED ON THE COMIC SERIES
BLAZING TRANSFER STUDENT
Blazing Transfer Students are agents
（天の声）
炎の転校生とは
問題がある学校に潜入し
悪を断つ
who infiltrate troubled schools
and stamp out the evil that afflicts them.
エージェントたちの
名称である
This is the story
of seven new Blazing Transfer Students.
今 ここに
新たに７人の
炎の転校生が誕生した
〜
（滝沢(たきざわ)）今回の転校先は ここだ
This is the next school
you'll be transferring to.
（日花里(ひかり)）私立鬼子母(きしぼ)学園
Kishibo Private Academy.
最近 ある生徒が
この学園のトップに君臨し
Recently, a certain student
has taken control of this school.
He has been forcing the students
and the staff
身勝手なルールを定めては
to follow the rules he came up with.
他の生徒や先生を
抑圧しているらしいの
（シゲオカ）
一体 何が起きてんねん？
How the heck did that happen?
How ugly!
（フジイ）美しくないな
（カミヤマ）
なんて ひどい顔なんだ
What an awful face!
（ナカマ）
あの頭髪の乱れ具合から
計算すると…
Judging from the way
his hair was blowing...
the wind speed was 30 meters per second.
風速 約30メートル
（コタキ）風？
Wind?
Your mission is to turn this school
back to normal.
今回のミッションは
この学校に平和を取り戻すことよ
早速
転校してもらう駆(かける)君を決めるわ
I will now select the Kakerus
to be transferred.
ということは
This is the perfect chance
to impress Hikari.
絶好の日花里ちゃんへの
アピールチャンスやろ
ここでや こいつら
出し抜いたったらええんちゃう？
I can get ahead of these other guys
through this mission!
（ハマダ）心の声 だだ漏れだな
We can all hear what you're thinking.
さっさと行ってらっしゃい
Get out there now!
SCREAMING
（キリヤマ）
うぇ〜！ でらすげえな おい！
That's freaking crazy!
（コタキ）うおっ！ え？
（シゲオカ）うわ〜！
-What? What's going on?
-This is nuts!
（カミヤマ）もう 最悪！
（シゲオカ）
もう 絶対ここ間違ってる！
This can't be the right place!
（カミヤマ）急ごう
Damn it! Let's get out of here!
（シゲオカ）もう！
Let's go!
（カミヤマ）早く！
（コタキ）おう
TEARFUL V!!
-I'm cold!
-I'm all wet!
（花園(はなぞの)）待て
Stop!
ここは まだ通せん
You cannot pass yet!
（コタキ）
俺は こう見えても
幼稚園のころから
I may not look like it, but I've had
perfect attendance since pre-school.
皆勤賞記録を更新中なんだよ
Sorry, but I'm not letting my record
end here.
悪いが ここで記録が
途絶えるわけにはいかねえんだよ
（金剛地(こんごうち)）下がれ 下がれ 下がれ！
Step back!
（花園）ああっ！
（金剛地）あっ！
（コタキ）ん？
（花園）
神宮寺(じんぐうじ)君 今日も一番乗りだね
Jinguji, you've arrived first again today!
（金剛地）さすがだね 神宮寺君
-You're amazing, Jinguji!
-That's right!
今日は一段と早いんじゃない？
You're here earlier than usual.
What did you have for breakfast?
（花園）朝は 何食べたの？
（シゲオカ）分からへん
What's going on?
（チャイム）
（コタキ）あっ！
俺の皆勤賞記録が…
My perfect attendance record!
Okay, this is a very important point.
（教師）
よし じゃあ ここ 大事だからな
This will be on the test.
ここ 試験に出るからな
Sorry we're late.
（シゲオカ）遅れて すみません
（教師）君たちは転校生の…
-Are you the transfer students?
-Hey!
（神宮寺）あれれれ？
I don't appreciate transfer students
being late on their first day.
転校初日から遅刻なんて
感心しないね
（コタキ）てめえは さっきの…
You're those guys from earlier.
Damn you for ruining
my perfect attendance record!
よくも 俺の皆勤賞記録を
邪魔してくれたな！
Watch your mouth!
（教師）
君！
口の利き方に気をつけなさい！
（コタキ）は？
What?
That's right.
そうだよ
この学校じゃ
僕がルールなんだからね
I'm in charge of this school, you know.
てめえ 何 言ってやがる？
Who do you think you are?
いちばん最初に学校に来るのは？
Who arrives at school first?
（生徒たち）神宮寺君！
-Jinguji!
いちばん成績がいいのは？
Who has the best grades?
-Jinguji!
（生徒たち）神宮寺君！
Who's the most popular with girls?
いちばん女の子にモテモテなのは？
-Jinguji!
（生徒たち）神宮寺君！
何なんだよ 一体？
What the hell's going on here?
Jinguji has to be number one
at everything.
神宮寺君は
何でも一番じゃなきゃダメなんだよ
Even when he arrives at school?
学校に来るタイミングぐらい
よくない？
That's right!
ダメだね！
そうだ 先生！
Teacher, since they were late
on their first day of school,
they must receive
転校の初日に遅刻したら…
Typhoon Generation punishment.
“台風ジェネレーションの刑”
にしようよ
-"Typhoon Generation"?
-That's a storm!
た… 台風ジェネレーション？
嵐かよ
（シゲオカ）うわ〜！
（カミヤマ）え？ え？
上等だよ
Bring it on.
君にロックオン
I've got you in my sights.
WHOOSH
（神宮寺）アハハハ！
（コタキ）うわ！ うっ…
WHOOSH
俺のリーゼント！
My pompadour hairdo!
Stop!
ストップ！
アハハ アハハ…
な… なんて恐ろしい技や
What a frightening punishment!
What do you think?
ねえ どう？
You can see why I'm the best now, right?
これで
僕が一番だって分かったでしょ？
How dare you ruin
my precious pompadour hairdo?
俺の自慢のリーゼントに
何しやがる！
You still don't get it, do you?
まだ分かんないようだね
WHOOSH
うわ〜！
くっそ〜！
Damn you!
SMACK
ママ〜！
Mommy!
（神宮寺の泣き声）
（花園･金剛地）
お前ら… 大変なことになるぞ！
-You're in big trouble now!
Jinguji!
（花園）神宮寺君！
Is that the guy calling the shots
at this school?
（コタキ）
あいつが
この学校を牛耳ってる生徒か？
-He wasn't such a big deal after all.
-Right.
（シゲオカ）
その割に大したことなかったけどね
You don't know how terrifying
Jinguji really is.
（男子）
君たちは 神宮寺君の本当の怖さを
知らないんだ
（校内放送のチャイム）
（校内放送）
転校生のシゲオカ駆君
コタキ駆君 カミヤマ駆君
The transfer students Kakeru Shigeoka,
Kakeru Kotaki, and Kakeru Kamiyama.
Come to the principal's office
immediately.
至急 校長室まで来てください
The principal's office?
（シゲオカ）校長室？
I have a bad feeling about this.
（カミヤマ）
嫌な予感しかしないんだけど
（コタキ）よし…
（校長）うう〜！
うう〜っ…
（光子(みつこ)）オ〜ッホホホ！
Such an unsightly face!
ぶざまな顔ね
オホホホ…
Are you all right, sir?
大丈夫かよ おっさん！
おい！
You're the transfer students
that bullied Hajime, aren't you?
あなたたちね？
はじめちゃんをいじめた転校生は
WHOOSH
SWOOSH
Stop!
（神宮寺）ストップ〜！
（コタキ）ハア ハア…
お前ら！
It's you guys!
Didn't I tell you I was in charge of
this school?
（神宮寺）
だから言ったでしょ？
僕がルールだって
（校長）神宮寺君は…
Jinguji is
the heir to Jinguji Group
that has funded our school
潰れかけた うちの学園に
資金提供してくださってる—
which was on the verge of going bankrupt.
神宮寺グループの御曹司(おんぞうし)なんだよ！
母親の権力の傘に隠れて
好き勝手やってるっちゅうわけか！
So, you're doing as you please,
hiding behind the power of your mom!
はじめちゃんは
一番になるために生まれてきたの
Hajime was born to be number one.
He must be number one at all times.
何でも一番じゃなきゃいけないのよ
ね？
Understand?
THUMP THUMP
（神宮寺）分かってるよ ママ
I know, Mommy.
I'll be number one in grades, sports,
and everything.
心配しなくても
成績も スポーツも 何でも一番だよ
Don't you worry!
（光子）うん ウフフ…
Hold on here!
（カミヤマ）ちょっと待って！
そんな作られた一番に…
What's the point of being number one
when everything is done for you?
何の意味があるっていうんだ！
Are you really satisfied with that,
Jinguji?
神宮寺君…
君は それでいいの？
I don't understand your question.
質問の意味が分からないな
Jinguji,
神宮寺君…
本当は つらいんじゃない？
-you're suffering inside, aren't you?
-Shut up!
うるさい！
僕はママのために
一番じゃなきゃダメなんだ
For Mom, I must be number one.
I know! Let's have a competition!
よし！ 勝負しよう
If you defeat me,
もし 僕に勝てたら
I'll do whatever you ask of me.
君たちの言い分を聞いてあげるよ
（コタキ）
フッ 相手になってやるよ
Challenge accepted.
（ママたち）いっち に…
One, two!
Aren't you going to face us?
おめえが戦うんじゃねえのかよ！
子供がママの助けを借りるのは
当然だろ？
It's only natural that
a child gets help from his mom.
（花園･金剛地）ママ〜！
-Mom!
-Do your best!
ファイト〜！
ってか
なんでバレーボールなんだよ！
Why are we playing volleyball?
ママさんっていったら
ママさんバレーに決まってるでしょ
Haven't you heard
about Mom Volleyball Team?
（神宮寺）ママ！
Mom!
Prove them that I'm number one!
僕が一番だってとこ
見せつけてやってよ
（光子）うぅ〜ん！
Don't you think it's lame
to ask your mom to prove that?
（シゲオカ）
ママが見せつけるって
メチャクチャやと思うんですけど！
（コタキの舌打ち）
KISHIBO
（シゲオカ）カミヤマ
Hey, Kamiyama.
おい！ おい 大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
（コタキ）カミヤマ てめえ
Kamiyama.
Do your best.
しっかりやれよ
うん
Okay.
（シゲオカ）よし！
All right.
はい いこう！
Come on, let's go.
（天の声）
鬼子母学園の
ママさんバレーっちゅうのは
The volleyball game against Kishibo Moms
is a special three-on-three match.
３対３の特別ルールなの
えい！
WHAM
（コタキ）痛(いて)っ！
What the hell are you doing?
てめえ 何すんだよ カミヤマ！
やっちゃった… ごめんなさい！
Goodness, I'm sorry.
（ママたち）アッハッハ…
Okay, serve it with all your might!
（シゲオカ）
はいはいはい！
思い切って いくぞ 思い切って！
Okay.
うん
思い切って 思い切って…
Serve with all my might.
えい！
Ouch!
（コタキ）痛〜っ
カミヤマ
お前 わざとやってんだろうが！
That was on purpose, wasn't it?
（カミヤマ）違う 違う！
（シゲオカ）ちょっと待て！
-I'll kill you!
-No, it wasn't.
（シゲオカ）わざとじゃない！
（カミヤマ）ごめん！
-No, I didn't mean to do that.
-Hold on!
（ママたち）オホホホ！
-Kotaki!
-He was aiming at my head!
（シゲオカ）コタキ！
（コタキ）俺の頭に当てた！
-That hurts!
-I wasn't!
Cut it out!
これから ママさんの実力を
見せつけてやるわ！
Now, it's time to show you
our true talent.
よし…
（光子）必殺…
My killer serve,
“エーゲ海の風”！
Wind of the Aegean Sea!
Ready.
せ〜の
-Go!
（ママたち）そ〜れ！
こんなサーブ 余裕やんけ
What a weak serve.
How is this a killer serve?
どこが必殺なんだよ
フッ
BAM
うおっ！
コタキ君！
-Kotaki!
-The ball curved.
ボールが曲がった！ 魔球か！
A screwball?
果たして
最後まで立っていられるかしら？
I wonder if you can last the whole game.
オホホホ！
なかなか やるじゃねえか
That was pretty good.
-Go!
（２人）そ〜れ！
（コタキ）油断するなよ
-Stay on guard.
-Kamiyama!
カミヤマ！
WHACK
（カミヤマ）コタキ君！
（ママたち）わ〜！ オホホ！
Kotaki!
（光子）
ママさんにバレーで勝とうなんて
10年 早いのよ
You're no match for us,
Mom Volleyball Team.
アッハッハ…
あれ！
What's that?
Our teamwork is the result
of our love for our children.
（光子）
親子の絆が成せるチームワークよ
何が絆だ こら！
You call that love?
ママ！
Mom!
Keep your eyes on the prize. Do your best.
よそ見してる暇はないよ
頑張って！
You're right!
（光子）そうね うん！ ウフフッ
次は“スペイン風邪”よ
Next is Wind of Spain.
（一同）えっ？
-What?
分からないの？ あなたたち
Don't you know what that is?
射(う)ってやる！
I'll crush you!
（ママたち）そ〜れ！
-Go!
BASH!
またか！
-Not again.
-Kotaki!
コタキ！
（ママたちの笑い声）
I swear I'll kick their asses.
ぜってえ ぶっ潰してやる
よっしゃ〜！ うお〜！
Yes!
（３人）ハア ハア…
Hold on.
You transfer students are pathetic.
ぶざまだね 転校生
（カミヤマ）神宮寺君
Jinguji.
僕は…
I want to compete against you!
君と勝負がしたいんだよ！
だったら まずは
ママを倒してからにしてほしいな〜
Then, you should defeat Mom first.
If you depend on your mom for everything,
そうやって
いつもママを頼りにして
you'll never be able to do anything
on your own!
自分一人じゃ
何もできないんだろ！
お黙りなさい！
Silence!
はじめちゃんがケガでもしたら
どうするの？
What if my Hajime gets injured?
じゃあ 君は
ママがケガしてもいいのか！
So, you don't care
if your mom gets injured?
ああ もう うるさい！
Enough, shut up!
（花園の母）光子さん チャンス！
This is our chance, Mitsuko.
（コタキ）うわっ！
SLIDE
ううっ…
てめえら いいかげんにしろよ
I've had enough of you.
ヤバい… コタキ 完全にキレた
Oh, shit, Kotaki's totally pissed off now.
うお〜！
RUMBLE
Now, that's a Blazing Transfer Student!
それでこそ 炎の転校生や！
俺も便乗させてもらうで！
I'll join you!
しゃ〜！
RUMBLE
僕も！
Me too.
ふん〜っ…
ぬっ！
FIZZLE
あれ？
これが とどめよ！
This will end all.
炎のレシーブ！
Blazing Receive!
ボールが燃えた！
The ball's on fire.
Here it comes, Kamiyama.
いくで カミヤマ
え？ え… うん！
Blazing Toss!
（シゲオカ）炎のトスだ！
だあっ！
Blazing Spike!
（カミヤマ）炎のアタック！
That's hot.
あっち〜！
（金剛地の母）うわ〜！
（光子）あ〜！
-Mom!
（２人）ママ！
（コタキ）ハア ハア…
Shigeoka? Kotaki?
シゲオカ君 コタキ君…
（救急車のサイレン）
（２人）ママ ママ…
-Mom?
Mom, are you okay?
ママ 大丈夫？
Slowly.
ああ ゆっくり…
Mom.
ママ 分かる？
-Step back, please.
-Mom.
（看護師）大丈夫ですか？
What should we do?
（カミヤマ）シゲオカ君
Shigeoka?
大丈夫？
-Are you okay?
-Can you hear me? Are you okay?
（救急隊員）
聞こえますか？ 大丈夫ですか？
（カミヤマ）
ねえ… ねえ シゲオカ君
Shigeoka.
起きてよ しっかりしてよ
Wake up.
Pull yourself together, Kotaki.
コタキ君！
（救急隊員）大丈夫
（カミヤマ）でも…
-It's all right.
-But...
ねえ 大丈夫でしょ？
Will they be all right?
ねえ シゲオカ君 コタキ君！
Shigeoka, Kotaki!
（２人）
カミヤマ… あとは お前に任せたぜ
-Kamiyama.
-It's in your hands now.
待って シゲオカ君 コタキ君
Shigeoka, Kotaki.
I can't do this all alone!
僕一人じゃ無理だよ！
SALUTE
嫌… 嫌だよ
Wait!
待ってよ〜！
（泣き声）
火遊びの代償は高くつくわよ
You must pay the price
for playing with fire.
What?
ここからは１対１の勝負ね
It's a one-on-one face-off now!
（光子）はっ！
（カミヤマ）えい！
（カミヤマ）うっ…
うっ…
（光子）
なんで
はじめちゃんの邪魔をするの？
Why are you causing Hajime trouble?
（カミヤマ）
あなたが… 甘やかしてるからです
Because you're spoiling him!
母親なんだから当然よ！
It's only natural since I'm his mom!
WHACK
息子のためだけの人生で
いいんですか？
Do you want to live your life
only for your child?
私の生きがいは
はじめちゃんなのよ
My whole reason for living is Hajime.
（カミヤマ）あなたは…
But...
ママである前に
一人の女性なんじゃないんですか？
you're not just a mom.
You're a woman as well.
How dare you?
一体 あなたに何が分かるのよ
What do you know about me?
光子さん！
Mitsuko!
どうして 私の名前を？
How do you know my name?
これを見てごらんよ
Look at this.
ほら…
See?
少し光を当てるだけで
こんなにも きれいなんだよ？
Look how beautiful you are
when you're dressed up a little.
これが…
This...
is me?
私？
神宮寺君
Jinguji.
もしも モナリザの絵が
その価値に気付かれず
What would have happened if the beauty
of the Mona Lisa was never realized...
ほこりをかぶっていたら
どう思う？
and ended up covered in dust?
ルーブル美術館は
有名にならなかった
The Louvre wouldn't have become famous.
That's not what I meant.
そうじゃない！
もったいないと思わないか？
Don't you think it's a waste?
こんなにボロボロになってる
君のママだって
Even your tired and weakened mom
きれいな額で飾れば
モナリザになれるのに…
can become a piece of art as well
if she's put in a beautiful frame!
ママはモナリザじゃない！
Mom's not the Mona Lisa!
そう！ ママはママよ
That's right.
Mom is a mom.
ママじゃない 神宮寺光子さんだ！
You're not just a mom.
You're Mitsuko Jinguji!
（光子）あっ…
（天の声）
お気付きだろうか
お気付きよ
Surely, you must have noticed by now.
カミヤマが
熟女大好きチキチキ
Kamiyama is a huge admirer
of mature women.
そう！ このとき
Kamiyama's love for this mature woman
has burst into a blazing ball of flame.
熟女好きだった
カミヤマの炎の思いが…
爆発！ ブワ〜ン！
"MEDITATION" FROM THAÏS
JULES MASSENET
ほら
Don't you see?
こんなにも きれいじゃないか
Look how beautiful you are.
もったいないよ
It's a waste.
きれい？
Am I beautiful?
顔なんか赤くしちゃって…
The way you blush...
かわいいな もう
is so pretty!
かわいい？
I'm pretty?
ママ しっかりしてよ！
Mom!
Pull yourself together. Get up!
立つんだ ママ！
光子さん
Mitsuko.
カミヤマ君…
Kamiyama.
きれいだよ 光子さん
You're beautiful, Mitsuko.
カミヤマ… 君
Kamiyama.
うわ〜！
ママ！
Mommy!
Substitution!
選手交代だ！
（光子）はじめちゃん？
Hajime?
Jinguji.
神宮寺君
それでこそ 男だ！
You're a real man now.
さあ 自分の力で
嵐を巻き起こしてみせなよ！
Okay.
Use your own strength
to show me what you can do!
ママは 誰にも渡さない！
I won't let anyone take Mom away from me!
うっ！
うう…
うえ〜ん
（カミヤマと神宮寺の泣き声）
ううっ…
うわ〜！
（天の声）
そら まさに号泣バレー
This is called Bawling Volleyball.
They unleash unbelievable power
as they sob endlessly.
泣きじゃくった２人は
驚くべきパワーを発揮した
泣き虫が暴れだすと
手がつけられないというアレである
No one can have the crybabies
under control when they've gone mad.
Ｖの涙アタック！
Victory Tears Spike!
はじめちゃん 危ない！
Watch out, Hajime.
はじめちゃん！
Hajime!
ああっ…
BAM
はじめちゃん！
Hajime.
はじめちゃん…
Hajime?
どうして？
Why did you do that?
Mom.
ママ… 大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Why did you protect me?
どうして 私なんかを かばったの？
（神宮寺）だって…
Because...
きれいなママでいてほしいから
I want you to stay beautiful, Mom.
ありがとう カミヤマ君
Thank you, Kamiyama.
僕の唯一の友達
This is my only friend.
カメリオ
Kamelio.
But, that's precious to you.
（光子）そんな大切なものを…
STRETCH
I'll take good care of it.
大切にするよ
（光子）はじめちゃん
Hajime?
はじめちゃん…
Thus, the Jingujis' tyrannical rule
of the school came to an end.
（天の声）
かくして 神宮寺親子の
あちゃらか支配は終焉(しゅうえん)を迎え
Game, set, and match point!
Kishibo Academy has returned to normal.
リーチ満貫 鬼子母学園に
平和が訪れちゃったの巻
（光子）
あなたは もう１人でも大丈夫
You'll be fine alone now.
I will go on a journey
to find my feminine side.
ママは 女を取り戻す旅に出るわ
Hajime.
はじめちゃん
強く… 強く生きるのよ！
Be strong.
I know you can do it.
Mom, please be more beautiful
than you are now when you come back.
ママも もっといい女になって
帰ってきてね
当たり前よ　うん！
I will!
（校長）いってらっしゃいませ
Have a good trip.
ありがとう
Thank you.
晩ご飯には帰ってくるから
I'll be home in time for dinner.
ありがとう カミヤマ君
Thank you...
Kamiyama.
気をつけて 奥さん
Take care,
Mrs. Jinguji.
I will.
うん！
（日花里）
コタキ君の弱点 リーゼント崩壊
Kotaki's weakness is the destruction
of his pompadour hairdo.
シゲオカ君 存在感なし
Shigeoka has zero presence.
カミヤマ君 熟女好き
Kamiyama loves mature women.
Are we really going to select one
from this group?
あの… 本当に
この中から１人を絞るんですか？
（滝沢）うっ うん… う〜ん
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey